Previously on From...
You can't keep
punishing yourself, Boyd.
She wouldn't have wanted that.
And I wish you had
the luxury of grief,
but you don't.
These people need you.
I knew all about the divorce
and how this whole trip
was just one last hurrah
before you sat us down
to break the news.
Thomas is dead!
You have two other kids!
Why aren't we enough for you?
Hello?
Is anybody out there?
Seriously, man, I don't know why
you keep staring at that thing.
Yeah, there's two pages
stuck together here.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Holy shit.
I have Sara tied up
in the basement of the church.
She showed me this.
Something was
watching me that day,
the same thing that told Sara...
And you think this thing
is trying to help us?
Whatever it is, it's a part
of the fabric of this place.
They're in the house!
They're inside!
Follow protocol!
Find your buddy,
get into the van!
Ellis! We have to
get back in the house!
We have to get inside!
I have an idea. Come on!
Please, please, please, please!
We have to go.
Go where?
Where are we going?
You go first.
I'll follow you down.
We need to get to town.
No. We have to go to the trees.
You're crazy.
You have to get inside.
- The tree? No! No!
- You'll be safe!
- What?
- I promise.
Find your brother.
You have to tell him.
I'll be right behind you!
No!
No, come here!
Stay with me.
Hey, Sheriff?
Yep.
In a sec.
I got, uh...
I got most of the Colony House
residents squared away.
Most people in town aren't
really using their basements,
so each house is
gonna take two or three.
Some are at the clinic and, uh,
the last three are gonna
stay with me and my mom...
and Jade, I guess.
Okay.
Feels like things are starting
to get tense out there.
People are already
boarding up their windows,
and with Colony House and
the town living together now,
I think maybe we should get
everyone gathered together
and, I don't know,
say something?
It's a good idea.
You should do that.
I think it would mean
a lot more coming from you.
Right.
Are you okay?
He saved my life.
You know that?
Father Khatri,
the night we got into town,
he risked his own life
to make sure that...
- Give everyone my regards.
- Wait. Where are you going?
I got something to do.
It's important.
More important than this?
Sheriff, the people
need you right now.
- They need to hear that...
- What?
They need to hear what?
Everything's gonna be okay?
That God's got a plan.
Look, if you're gonna be
the sheriff when I'm gone,
you're gonna need to start
figuring out how to say things
like that for yourself
and sound halfway convincing.
You'll do fine.
Let's take a walk.
Listen to how
peaceful that sounds.
The man is riding
a pony on an ocean.
You know why?
'Cause he has a boat.
Doesn't matter how many times
you listen to the song,
still can't afford
to buy a boat.
Yeah, look, all I'm saying is
if we manage the payments...
Oh, we're gonna
manage the payments?
- Yeah!
- Right.
So, is not paying the payments
one of the management options?
Because that's
the option we'd be taking.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure most
lenders frown on that option.
Yeah, yeah. Listen,
nobody's talking to you.
All right? Nobody.
You know what they used
to call e in the army, right?
Mr. Fish and Loaves.
That's right!
That's right! That's right!
They'd send me to
any base to set it up,
and no matter what they gave me,
no matter what the resources,
I would make it work.
Yes, sir, that's right.
Mr. Fish and Loaves.
...Loaves.
Yeah, but, you know, didn't
they call mom Iron Abby?
They certainly did.
And don't you forget it.
Yeah, yeah.
I hear you.
The problem with iron is...
rigid.
So, sometimes, you know,
it doesn't know when to bend.
Uh-huh.
Babe... Babe...
all I'm saying,
all I'm saying is, a boat,
you know, wouldn't be
a bad retirement gift.
In case you
needed some ideas
on how to help me, you know,
smooth my transition
from a long and decorated
military career to, you know,
this strange and mysterious
civilian life.
And a boat... Babe, what are...
what are you looking for?
My-my Chapstick. I can't
find anything in this bag.
Can you hold this for me?
Sure.
What is... Is...
This...
This looks like a boat key.
- What?
Yeah, why am I holding
a-a boat key?
Wait, did you buy the boat?
Oh, shit.
Of course we
bought you a boat!
- Oh, snap!
- If I had to listen to that man
sing about Tonto and
his pony one more time,
I'd throw myself into traffic.
- Oh, snap!
- Happy retirement, Dad!
You bought me a boat, baby!
- Thank you!
- Dad!
Oh!
Oh, God.
Please,
can you just tell me
where we're going?
Where's Father Khatri?
They used to shriek.
Did you know that?
All night long, they'd shriek.
Drove people crazy.
That all stopped
once we got the talismans.
Then they started to whisper.
I always wondered about that.
Your voices tell you
anything about that?
No.
'Course not. God forbid
they tell you anything useful.
Keep walking.
Not until you
tell me what's going on.
You think you're
gonna stand there
and make demands
after what you did?
Where is Father Khatri?
He's dead!
What?
Those things got
into Colony House.
Father Khatri tried to help.
Now he's dead,
along with a lot
of other people.
Is Ellis okay?
He's fine.
He's scraped up.
He's back at the clinic
with the others.
Oh, now you wanna cry.
You cry like that
for Bing Qian?
You think I'm a monster.
I don't give
two shits what you are.
The only reason you're alive
is because Father Khatri
thought you could
help us all get home.
The second you prove him wrong,
I'm gonna put
a bullet in you myself.
Now, keep walking.
- Where are we going?
- I said keep walking!
So, I'll make up some beds
for you in the basement.
Uh, bathroom's in the back and
feel free to use the kitchen,
but you've gotta
respect the rations.
It won't be the most
comfortable thing in the world,
but we should have Colony House
back up
and running pretty soon, so...
What the fuck is this?
Uh, we're gonna have a few more
house guests for a little while.
And how little
is a little while?
Aren't you the guy that thought
this was a giant escape room?
How'd that work out for you?
- Fuck off.
- Okay.
All right,
this is bullshit, okay?
They chose the flower.
They don't belong here.
Dude, why don't
you just...
All right,
any of you guys know Victor?
All right, where's he squatting?
I need to find him.
I saw him running
towards the woods
with the Matthews
girl last night.
Fantastic.
See what a little intercommunity
cooperation can do?
Kumbay-fucking-ya!
Let's get inside.
That guy's
the fuckin' worst.
I don't...
I don't even understand.
It was like one second everyone
was having such a good time...
How... How did you
get out of the house?
I was... I was up in
Victor's room and we...
No. It...
- It wasn't like that. We were...
- Julie...
No, he was stacking
all of these,
and it looked like he was
getting ready to leave.
And then,
when the screaming started,
we climbed out his window,
and he said we had
to go to the forest.
And then, we ran to this tree
and then he pushed me inside...
- Hey.
- And I...
He said it was starting.
What was starting?
I don't know. He...
All I know is, one second,
I was in a tree,
and the next, I was in a
giant cabinet in a root cellar.
How is that possible?
You went through a Farway Tree!
Huh?
Victor said you can
go all sorts of places.
And sometimes people
go to different places.
So, maybe he went
somewhere else.
We have to find him!
One step at a time.
Hey, Julie...
Jules...
Hey, Jules.
Julie...
What's happening to us?
What...?
- Honey...
- What is going on?
What's happening?
We're digging a big hole
in the basement.
We're gonna find out where
the electricity comes from.
Hey, hey. No.
Jules, we're gonna be fine.
Breathe.
I know.
Everything's gonna be okay.
- Yes.
- No! How can you say that?
What part of this is okay?
Honey, oh my God.
Just...
Ah. Good, you're here.
Have you seen Victor?
- Hey!
- One of the squatters
at my house said you ran off to
the woods with him last night!
Ow! Ow!
Hey!
I need to talk to her!
What is wrong with you?!
Do you have any idea
what she has been through?
Look, believe me, I get it.
Times are tough all around.
But I found
something last night!
There is this symbol that
I've been... I've been seeing.
The same symbol is in this book.
And last night, okay,
last night,
I found this photo!
I don't give a shit
about your questions
and your symbol and your books.
Just stay the fuck away
from my daughter.
You understand me?
Okay, you're doing the whole
protective dad thing.
I respect that.
You dragged me out
into the woods,
have me climb a fuckin' tree
for some stupid idea,
and then you
run off like a psycho
before we even have
a chance to try it.
Yeah, uh,
I'm sorry about that...
It worked.
- Wait. What?
- Yeah.
All I got was some static,
but it worked.
I think if we get it
up over the tree line,
and we get it enough power,
I think we could
get a signal out.
Wait, wait, wait.
How do you propose we
get up over the tree line?
We start by going
to the high ground.
Jesus. That's grim.
Where are
all the people?
I mean...
Wait!
- Whoa, Boyd!
- Jesus!
Hey!
Hey, hey, back up!
Back up!
You tryin' to get
yourself killed?
I need you to
listen to me, please.
Okay?
There isn't much time.
Now, this is gonna
sound very, very strange,
and you're not
gonna believe me,
and I wouldn't
believe me either. Okay?
And I wish there was
more time to explain.
But if you don't come
with me right now,
you're all going to die.
- Oh...
- Okay, whoa, whoa, whoa, Mom.
Mom, what the hell
are you doing?
Okay, you have a gun.
That is good.
And you're welcome to keep it
pointed at me the entire time.
But I am begging you,
please come with me.
Go on.
Drive away. Drive away.
No, no, no, no. Please.
What the hell was that?
That was death,
and it's coming...
right now.
Please.
Let's go.
You can put that thing away now.
The only things that are
gonna hurt you are out there,
and that thing's not gonna
make a damn bit of difference
if they find us.
Look, I know you
all have questions.
And, I promise, we will talk
when the sun comes up.
- Okay.
- Ah...
- Here we go, all right?
- Okay.
- Nice and slow.
It's gonna hurt a bit.
Just breathe.
- Yeah.
- Good, good, good.
There we go.
Breathe.
Good.
Breathe, breathe, breathe.
Relax. Down. Good.
Okay, see?
Good as new.
Yeah.
- All right.
- Yeah.
Just gonna put a sling on here.
Can I help with anything?
Make sure
he doesn't get out of bed. Okay?
I don't want you going anywhere
until I can give you
a solid once-over.
- Yeah.
- All right?
Here we go. You good?
Be back in
a second, okay?
Thank you.
Hey.
Busy day for you.
Uh, yeah, we're
a little short-handed.
What can I do?
Well, I could use some help
getting this place
a bit more secure.
It's gonna be a full house
tonight, given what happened.
- So...
- Yeah, of course.
Oh, I, um...
I, uh...
I finished Chapter 6. It's...
Things are starting
to get interesting.
Yeah, I don't think
it's gonna be
much of a reading
night tonight, but, uh,
yeah, I'll try to check it out.
Cool.
Thanks, Deputy.
Donna.
You got a minute?
How's Julie?
She's okay.
She's, uh...
But that...
that's not why I'm here.
We came because
we need your help.
With what?
We wanna build a tower
and we wanna
put it on the roof.
What?
We think if we can
get it high enough,
we could
broadcast a signal
that anyone else
in the area could hear.
And what area
is that exactly?
Look, whatever
this place is,
wherever this place is,
radio signals work
in ways that we can't.
And we already got a strong
indication that this could work.
Well...
We got a little static.
C... Colony House
is the highest point
on the highest hill.
And if we build a tower
and we put it up there,
we could broadcast out a signal
that could get up over
any interference
from the forest canopy.
Sure.
You're okay with this?
You know how many people
died here last night?
Fourteen.
Those things killed
14 of my people.
There are pieces of them
lying all over this hill.
And I don't think the others
are coming back any time soon.
So, we might as well use
the house for something.
Keep going.
Wait right there.
Let's go.
You're gonna sit tight here.
I'll be back before dark.
I've got a few things in town
to wrap up before we head out.
Head out where?
Find our way home.
You won't need those.
I'm not going anywhere.
I wanna help.
All I've ever
wanted to do is help.
There's nothing to
chain you to here anyway.
If you run...
I understand.
I'll be back.
My God.
Boyd.
Here. Come on.
Welcome to your
worst nightmare.
Look,
it's a...
it's a lot to unpack.
Just take it slow.
I'll explain more
at the diner.
At the what?
The diner.
It's, uh...
Meet me over there.
Hey.
You okay?
No, not really.
That's what you people
do every night here?
Here?
You hide and pray?
Well, there's really
not much else we can do.
And you don't know
anything else about this place?
Who built it?
How long's it been here?
Look, what we know
is what you see.
And the people here,
they just... they're just tryin'
to live through the night.
Doesn't give us much time
for anything else.
You gotta start
working together.
That's a little
easier said than done.
Yeah. Right.
So, you start small, right?
Gather your resources,
create a system, making sure
everybody's covered at night.
Nobody hides
in the same place twice.
You gotta get
these people to start
looking out for each other,
taking care of each other,
and then, you build from there.
Okay.
But where do we start?
All right.
Once we have
everything inventoried,
we're gonna start
rationing it out.
Donna here is
in charge of resupply.
So, you need anything,
you go see her.
Abby is gonna be
drawing up a system
for where we spend
the nights.
We're gonna start
digging up some new spots,
make sure we are
constantly rotating.
Let's not make it easy
for these things.
Come on.
What do you got?
All right.
Hey.
What are you doing?
Are you hungry?
No. Not really.
Have you eaten anything?
I don't know. No.
I'm gonna make you some food.
Are you and Dad still
getting a divorce?
I, uh...
I really don't have an answer
for you right now.
It's a simple question.
It's not
that simple, honey.
Hey. Hey.
You said you loved each other.
We do.
Then why?
- Is it me?
- No.
Did I do something wrong?
Oh, God, no.
No, no, no. No.
No, honey, you didn't
do anything wrong. Don't...
No.
Listen.
There are things that
you'll only understand
when you become a parent.
One of those things...
is that you live
for your children.
Your only job is... is
to love them and protect them.
So when Thomas died...
something inside of me broke.
And I have
no idea how to fix it.
I keep reliving that day.
It was just
such a normal day.
You and Ethan were
in the next room.
Your Dad and I
were in the kitchen,
and Thomas was in his changing
table right between us.
Then the phone rang.
I reached for the diaper
and your father reached
for the phone and...
we just turned for one second...
just one fucking second...
and he rolled off the table.
Your father
is the love of my life.
But sometimes I see him and...
I hear
that fucking phone ring.
Why didn't you tell me that?
Because no matter
how grown up you are,
you're always
gonna be my little girl.
So we pretended...
yeah, that everything was fine.
I think that just made
everything worse.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, too.
Let us in!
There's gonna be trouble if you
don't move outta the way!
- Let us in!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey!
What the hell's going on?!
Tom, Eli,
what the hell are you doing?
We got people from Colony House
in our houses,
using our supplies!
If I gotta choose between me
and some asshole from
Colony House raiding this place,
- then it's gonna be me!
- Nobody's raiding anything!
Well, those things weren't
supposed to be able
to get into Colony House either,
and look how that turned out!
- Exactly.
- Alright. So then, you guys...
You just wanna
throw it all away?
Start acting like animals
and make it all worse?
Look, we're gonna
figure this out.
Just... just go home.
Just go home, please.
They... scared.
Yeah.
Those things come out at night.
They walking around in
the forest during the daytime?
Not as far as we can tell.
There might be
resources out there.
We go scavenging
during the daytime,
never know what
we might find.
Yeah.
Good luck findin' volunteers.
Right.
We'll work on that part.
How long were you
in the military?
Uh, almost 30 years.
Hm.
Set up operations
in some of the biggest,
baddest clusterfucks
on the planet.
And your wife?
Abby was a Marine.
She's the badass
in the family.
Yeah.
Mom, you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine. I...
I was just thinking
about this dream I had
when I was a little girl.
I was...
Never mind.
We should go help your dad.
Lots to do.
Can't go, not now.
Damn near had
a riot at the diner.
But this is exactly
why you said you had to go.
Things are coming apart.
It's already starting to happen.
We lost over a dozen people
last night.
And we'll lose more if...
if they start to panic.
- At least if you...
- Kenny, enough.
I'll stay until
things settle down.
And what if they don't?
What if they don't?
Am I interrupting?
No, come on in.
Sheriff, please...
Kenny, we're done. Okay?
We're not done.
I said, we're not done.
You told me you had to go.
You told me
that I had to step up
and be strong
while you were gone.
You told me we were
running out of time,
and what part
of that's changed? Huh?
We've all been sitting
around the last few months,
acting like those
talismans were a solution.
Like they made us safe?
Well, guess what.
We were never safe.
Those talismans were a Band-Aid,
a... a temporary reprieve.
Things were never okay here,
and things are never
going to be okay here.
We need to find a way home
or else every
single person here
is gonna end up
exactly like Father Khatri.
There are answers out there,
and you're going to find them.
And in the meantime,
you need to get over
what happened last night.
You need to get
your shit together
and be the scary hard-ass
that you've always been
because that's who people
need you to be right now.
And if we're not gonna fight
like hell to go home,
then we might as well swallow
a fucking bullet right now.
Is that what you want?
I didn't know the little
bastard had that in him.
Now, how about you explain
what the fuck
he was talking about?
Where exactly are you going?
Let's take a walk.
I'll explain on the way.
Come on, man!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Come on!
Help me out a little bit here.
Hey!
Look what I found!
Okay, what? Where...
where did you...?
I... He was about half
a mile out, eating some grass.
There are chickens
out there too.
Tomorrow,
I'm gonna set up some traps.
There's chickens in the forest?
Yep.
Hey, you know what?
Grab some people.
We need to start rebuilding
that, uh, pen outside the barn.
Okay? Hey! Hey!
Hey.
- I found a goat.
- He got a goat.
Yeah, that's great.
Hey, uh, look,
I need to talk to you.
All right. Hey, could you
take him off my hands?
No.
Yeah, no, you got it.
Yeah, yeah.
He's not exactly what
I'd call cooperative,
but just hold the rope.
- Yeah.
- You got it.
- I, uh...
- You believe that?
I knew I was gonna find
something out in those woods.
I ain't think it was gonna be
livestock, but I'll take it.
Who knows what else might be...
You need to stop
going out there.
What?
It's Mom.
She's not doing well. Okay?
I mean, you've been going out
there for weeks now,
and you're not seeing
what's happening here.
I think this place is, like,
starting to get to her.
Okay.
Look, I know you're scared, man.
I'm fricking terrified.
But do me a favor. Look around.
The things we are doing
are working.
There are things out
in those woods that can help us,
things that might even...
All I know, all I know is that
the second we stop looking for
answers, that's when we lose.
Okay, so, then why don't
we just get someone else
to go and look for a while?
Dad, we need you here.
Mom needs you here!
Okay, look, she... she's not...
You know, sometimes,
I-I see her just standing,
staring off in the middle
of the road, like she's...
Your mom... Your mom is
as tough as they come.
Iron Abby, remember?
Now, I know this is hard,
but this is what we have to do,
at least for now.
You're not even listening
to what I'm saying to you!
Look, look, okay, okay.
Look, look. Look, look.
We got about four hours
of daylight left, right?
Help your mom get everybody
secured, tucked away.
And when I get home
tonight, we will talk.
I promise.
Dad, please...
just stay.
We will talk tonight.
Okay?
Go help your mom.
What are you doin' out here?
Well, you belong to someone.
Someone out here maybe?
You live out here
with someone, buddy?
It's okay.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I just wanna get
a closer look.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Hey!
What the...
No.
No, no.
Fuck!
What?
What the...
Luck, not skill.
Sheriff Stevens.
Heard you had a rough go of it
last night.
Sorry about Father Khatri.
Oh, I appreciate that.
I, uh...
Not sure if you heard,
but I'm setting off today.
Gonna find us a way
outta this place.
So, in other words, you're about
to go off into the woods
with no idea
what you're looking for.
Because that worked
so well last time.
Hey.
Right?
Fatima, would you
give us a second?
Yeah, of course.
Thank you.
You wanna be angry with me,
you wanna hate me, that's fine.
But I'm gonna say
a couple things and, uh,
and you're gonna listen,
whether you want to or not.
Go ahead.
If something happens
to me out there,
if I don't... make it back,
I never want you to regret
what you didn't say.
I never want you to feel...
I won't be here to
tell you that it's okay.
So, I'm telling you now.
Man, it's okay.
And that you are my son.
Mine.
I love you,
and I am proud of the man
that you have become.
And not a single day goes by
when that hasn't been true.
Okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's okay.
Okay.
How'd that go?
About as well
as could be expected.
He'll come 'round.
You really going?
Looks like.
You and me, we've had our
differences, but I just, uh...
Thank you...
for looking after him.
You've done
something I couldn't.
You did enough, Boyd.
You did more than anyone
should ever have to.
So, you come back, okay?
Who the hell else
am I gonna argue with?
Sure you'll find someone.
Fuck off.
- What?
- Come on.
Now, get the fuck outta here
before people start
thinking we're friends.
Yes, ma'am.
I'm gonna say something to you
that might make you hate me,
and if it does, that's okay.
What happened
wasn't your Dad's fault,
and it wasn't yours.
It was this place.
I wasn't here. I may not have
seen it, but I know your Dad.
I know that if
there was anything,
anything else he could've done,
he would've done it.
What happened was so awful...
it's almost inconceivable,
and it fills you with rage,
rage that you needed
to put somewhere.
And this whole time,
your dad let you put it on him
because that's what parents do.
But did you, for a second,
stop to consider
what that day was like for him,
what he's carried every
second of every day since?
If you don't get up
and go after him right now,
you're gonna regret it
for the rest of your life.
What's...
Babe?
Ab?
What's happening, Abs?
What's going on, Abs?
Abs?
Abby?
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Ab...
Please.
Please, why are you doing this?
It's okay.
It's not real.
It's a nightmare.
The only way for us to go home
is to wake everyone up.
It's okay.
You can't die in dreams.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Abby.
Abby, stop! Stop!
S-s-stop.
No. No.
Hey. Hey.
I found something,
s-something I think
is gonna help us.
You didn't come back
before it got dark.
There's no way you could
have survived out there,
not if it was real.
Yeah.
It's time to wake up.
It's time to wake everybody up.
Baby, please.
Baby...
Right! If I had a pony?
No, no!
Dad?
Ellis, what are
you doing out here?
Um...
I've been following you
since you left town.
I've been, um...
I've been trying to find the
courage to say something to you.
Look, last night, when, uh,
those things got inside
of Colony House,
Fatima and I,
we would've died.
I mean, there was no way
that we could've survived that.
But the one thing that saved us,
that saved her...
was the talisman on the door.
I've just been so angry
for a really long time...
...and I, uh...
I didn't know how to...
But, you know, if you
didn't do what you did,
if you didn't bring
those talismans back...
It wasn't your fault, Dad.
What Mom did,
it wasn't...
It wasn't your fault.
Look, I'm sorry.
Yeah, I'm so sorry, Dad.
I'm so sorry.
No, no, no, hey.
Hey, no.
It's okay. It's all right.
I just... I just didn't
want you to leave
without saying goodbye.
This is not goodbye.
Okay? You hear me? Huh?
Okay.
All right.
Hey.
What is she doing here?
Look, I need
to take her with me. Okay?
Wait, no, you know
what she tried to do!
No, no, no! Hey, look, look.
I need to take her with me
'cause she might be helpful
for us to find out
what we're looking
for out there, okay?
I will explain everything
to you when I get back.
We'll have a long conversation,
hopefully on our way
outta this place.
But for now, right now, I just
need you to trust me, okay?
Okay, no one can
know she's with me.
Can you do that for me?
Can you trust me?
Just come back.
Yes, sir.
All right.
Go on. Go.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Okay.
Yeah.
Look, we're in a tight spot.
No one's gonna
pretend otherwise.
But Sheriff Boyd
is risking everything for us
out there in the forest.
The least we can do is...
keep ourselves
together while he does.
So that means that we're gonna
do things a little differently
going forwards.
No more Colony House,
no more town.
We're a community, so...
we do this together.
All you Colony House folk,
I don't want any of you
being shitty houseguests.
Now, we're gonna get
the house put back together,
but first of all,
Jim here has an idea about
a way we might be able to get
a signal to folks
back in the world.
So we can either
put our energy towards
boarding up a bunch
of broken windows,
or we can help build
something that gets us all
out of this shithole.
Jim?
Well, we're gonna need supplies,
anything we can get
our hands on.
We're gonna need batteries,
anything with a charge.
But most of all,
we're gonna need people.
The sooner we get this built,
the sooner we can all go home.
Hey. You find him?
Can't take any chances.
Let's go.